Guide to the William L. Amoss papers 0251.UA
Special Collections and University Archives
William L. Amoss papers
1884-1936 and undated
1896-1919
Special Collections and University Archives
Amoss, William L.
0251.UA
14.00 Linear Feet
This collection contains materials relating to the career of William L. Amoss, who was head of the Farmers' Institutes at the Maryland Agricultural College from 1896 to 1910. Amoss's papers include daybooks, brochures, scrapbooks, reports and photographs, and cover such subjects as farmers' institutes, county fairs, farmers' markets, the Maryland State Grange of the Patrons of Husbandry, local farm clubs, the Louisiana Purchase Exhibition, poultry, horticulture, and transportation. In 1918 and 1919, Amoss served as Special Field Agent with the U.S. Employment Service of the Department of Labor. His papers from this period include correspondence regarding farm labor shortages suffered during and after World War I in New Jersey, Maryland, and Delaware. There is also a small amount of personal correspondence that provides some insight into Amoss's family life.
Use and Access to Collection
This collection is open for research.
Custodial History and Acquisition Information
The William L. Amoss papers were separated from the records of the Maryland Agricultural Experiment Station and accessioned by the University of Maryland University of Maryland in 1972. Originally, the collection included a series on the Farmers' Institutes. In 2005, that series was separated from the William L. Amoss papers and added to the the Farmers' Institutes records.
Biography
William Lee Amoss was born October 10, 1859, on Mt. Soma farm in Benson, Harford County, Maryland. He was educated at Oakland Academy and graduated with the equivalent of a high school degree from Eaton and Burnett Business College in Baltimore. In 1904, Amoss married Sarah Evelyn Breed, a native of Cornwall, New York. At the time of their marriage, Breed had been Superintendent of the Southern Industrial Classes of Norfolk, Virginia, a branch of the Hampton Institute, for eight years. The couple had at least one child, a daughter named Cornelia.
After serving for nine years as Secretary of the Harford County Farmers' Convention, Amoss was appointed the first director of the Department of Farmers' Institutes of the Maryland Agricultural College (MAC) in 1896. According to Amoss, his appointment came as a surprise and was accepted "only on the solicitation of friends with whom I had been associated when working for our farmers organizations for a betterment of conditions under which we were living." As director, he organized institutes in each county of the state, recruiting agricultural experts from around the country to speak to local farmers regarding the practical issues they faced every day, covering topics such as using fertilizer, raising livestock, and determining soil acidity, among many others. He reported to MAC President R.W. Silvester in 1907 that the Institutes had "shown [the farmer] that he must look to the Agricultural College and the Experiment Station for scientific information not to be obtained elsewhere." He remained director until 1910 when he was dismissed by the MAC Board of Trustees. The Board cited administrative concerns as the reason for Amoss's dismissal, indicating that the Farmers' Institutes had deviated from the Board's vision for the mission of the College. His dismissal was controversial, particularly with local farmers' organizations.
During his tenure at MAC, Amoss participated in a number of additional activities. He was one of the original founders of and subscribers to the Farmers Market Company of Baltimore City. Incorporated in 1896, it was commonly referred to as the Baltimore Market. Amoss was president of the American Association of Farmers' Institute Workers for the year 1902. In 1903 and 1904, Amoss spent a significant amount of time organizing Maryland's entry for an agricultural exhibit at the Louisiana Purchase Exposition in St. Louis, Missouri.
Amoss's name was submitted for the position of president of the Maryland Agricultural College in 1913 by George Powell, former director of the Farmers' Institutes for New York and president of the Agricultural Experts Association, though he was not ultimately considered. In 1918, Amoss was appointed Special Field Agent with the U.S. Employment Service of the Department of Labor. He dealt primarily with farm labor shortages suffered during and after World War I in New Jersey, Maryland, and Delaware. He resigned from that position in July 1919.
Amoss also maintained and developed his own farm, Mt. Soma - so named as the reverse spelling of Amos - in Benson, Harford County, Maryland. In his role as a farmer, Amoss continued to correspond regularly with state experiment stations and the U.S. Department of Agriculture. After his resignation from the U.S. Employment Service, he settled permanently into his work on Mt. Soma Farm with his family.
William Amoss died on December 11, 1933, at his residence on Mt. Soma farm. He was preceded in death by his wife.
Scope and Content of Collection
The William L. Amoss papers cover the years 1884 to 1936, with the bulk of the material dating between 1896 and 1919. Document types represented in the collection include correspondence, manuscripts, scrapbooks, ephemera, newspaper clippings, and publications. The materials cover topics such as the Farmers' Institutes and their administration; advice on farming and livestock, including letters and articles dealing with diseases of crops and livestock, methods of fertilization, soil testing, and the transportation of farm products; financial and labor aspects of farming, particularly during World War I; Maryland's participation in the Louisiana Purchase Exposition; and Amoss's participation in a number of farmers' organizations and clubs. There is also a small amount of personal correspondence that provides some insight into Amoss's family life.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into eight series.
Series 1
Subject Files
Series 2
Grange and Farm Clubs
Series 3
Correspondence
Series 4
Clippings
Series 5
Mt. Soma Farm
Series 6
Publications
Series 7
Photographs
Series 8
Memorabilia
Related Material
The Farmers' Institutes records include a series that was separated from the William L. Amoss papers. The Farmers' Institutes records are comprised almost exclusively of material dating from Amoss's tenure as Director.
The Cooperative Extension Service continued the work of the Farmers' Institutes. The Records of the Cooperative Extension Service date to its formation in 1914 and include materials related to Amoss's work regarding outreach to farmers.
The Maryland Agricultural Experiment Station records include records that overlap with Amoss's tenure as Director of the Farmers' Institutes. Amoss worked closely with the Agricultural Experiment Station and with its director, Harry Patterson.
Separated Material
A series comprised exclusively of Farmers' Institutes materials was separated and placed with the Farmers' Institutes records in the University of Maryland.
Although the William L. Amoss papers include a photograph series, some photographs originally accessioned with the William L. Amoss papers were separated from the collection in the 1980s and added to the photograph print files. They may be found under the subject heading "Amoss" in the "portrait" portion of that collection. Amoss photographs are also scattered throughout the photograph print files under the headings "University of Maryland -- Agricultural Experiment Station" and "University of Maryland -- Farmers' Institutes."
Farmers' institutes -- Maryland; Farm produce -- Maryland -- Marketing; Agricultural laborers -- United States; Amoss, William L. -- 1859-; Maryland Agricultural College; True, Alfred Charles, 1853-1929.; Pearson, Raymond A. (Raymond Allen), 1873-1939.; Rankin, F. H.; Van Wagnen, Jared.; Van Alstyne, Edward.; Silvester, Richard W. (Richard William), b. 1857.; Massey, W. F. (Wilbur Fisk), 1839-1923.; Wing, Joseph, 1810-1895.; Patterson, H. J. (Harry Jacob), 1866-1948
- Subject Files, 1895-1927; 1; 1.50 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  The Subject Files are comprised of correspondence, pamphlets, advertisements, and records covering agricultural topics such as dairying, farm buildings, and feeding. Files related to Amoss's work in various organizations, such as the Farmers Market Company of Baltimore, are included in this series. Also included are files related to subjects of active interest to Amoss, such as a study of state gambling laws and a related draft of a speech attributed to his wife, Sarah Evelyn Breed, correspondence drafted by Amoss to the State Highway Commission supporting construction of the Belair-Harford Turnpike between Belair, Reckord, and Baltimore in order to facilitate the transportation of produce to the Baltimore markets, and drafts of speeches covering topics such as the Farmers' Institutes, the contribution of the farmer to the war effort, and African-American farm labor. A significant portion of the Subject Files deals with Amoss's work on the Maryland exhibit at the 1904 St. Louis World's Fair (Louisiana Purchase Exposition). Arrangement is alphabetical by topic.
  - Agricultural Building, Maryland State College of Agriculture, 1916; 1.1.1 (Box 1, Folder 1.0)
  - Agricultural Extension Questionnaire, 1910; 1.1.2 (Box 1, Folder 2.0)
  - Alabama, 1916; 1.1.3 (Box 1, Folder 3.0)
  - American Association of Farmers Institute Workers, 1902-1913; 1.1.4 (Box 1, Folder 4.0)
  - Apple Tree Borers, 1907, 1914; 1.1.5 (Box 1, Folder 5.0)
  - Belair-Harford Turnpike, 1908-1909; 1.1.6 (Box 1, Folder 6.0)
  - Cooperatives, Undated; 1.1.7 (Box 1, Folder 7.0)
  - Corn, 1901-1903; 1.1.8 (Box 1, Folder 8.0)
  - Dairying, circa 1900; 1.1.9 (Box 1, Folder 9.0)
  - Farm Buildings, Undated; 1.1.10 (Box 1, Folder 10.0)
  - Farmers Market Company of Baltimore City, 1895-1896; 1.1.11 (Box 1, Folder 11.0)
  - Farmers Market Company of Baltimore City, 1897; 1.1.12 (Box 1, Folder 12.0)
  - Farmers Market Company of Baltimore City -- Incorporation, 1896; 1.1.13 (Box 1, Folder 13.0)
  - Farmers Market Company of Baltimore City -- Incorporation and Reports, 1896; 1.1.14 (Box 1, Folder 14.0)
  - Farmers Markets, 1911; 1.1.15 (Box 1, Folder 15.0)
  - Feeding, 1906-1927; 1.1.16 (Box 1, Folder 16.0)
  - Fertilizers, 1908; 1.1.17 (Box 1, Folder 17.0)
  - Gambling Report, 1908; 1.1.18 (Box 1, Folder 18.0)
  - Horticulture, 1907-1922; 1.1.19 (Box 1, Folder 19.0)
  - Lambs, 1905; 1.2.1 (Box 2, Folder 1.0)
  - Morrill Act, 1902-1907; 1.2.2 (Box 2, Folder 2.0)
  - Philadelphia Market, 1895-1896; 1.2.3 (Box 2, Folder 3.0)
  - Poultry, 1900-1928; 1.2.4; Includes oversize (Box 2, Folder 4.0)
  - Pruning, 1915; 1.2.5 (Box 2, Folder 5.0)
  - Refrigeration, 1896; 1.2.6 (Box 2, Folder 6.0)
  - Seeds, 1903-1906; 1.2.7 (Box 2, Folder 7.0)
  - Southern Industrial Classes, 1910-1912; 1.2.8 (Box 2, Folder 8.0)
  - Speeches, 1903-1910 and undated; 1.2.9 (Box 2, Folder 9.0)
  - State Museum, 1905; 1.2.10 (Box 2, Folder 10.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, 1903; 1.2.11 (Box 2, Folder 11.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, January - May 1904; 1.2.12 (Box 2, Folder 12.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, June - December 1904; 1.2.13 (Box 2, Folder 13.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, 1903-1906; 1.2.14 (Box 2, Folder 14.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, 1905-1906; 1.2.15 (Box 2, Folder 15.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, Clippings, 1903-1904; 1.3.1 (Box 3, Folder 1.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, Louisiana Purchase Exposition, Book I, 1903-1904; 1.3.2 (Box 3, Folder 2.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, Louisiana Purchase Exposition, Book I, 1903-1904; 1.3.3 (Box 3, Folder 3.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, Louisiana Purchase Exposition, Book I, 1903-1904; 1.3.4 (Box 3, Folder 4.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, Louisiana Purchase Exposition, Book II, 1903-1904; 1.3.5 (Box 3, Folder 5.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, Louisiana Purchase Exposition, Book II, 1903-1904; 1.3.6 (Box 3, Folder 6.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, Louisiana Purchase Exposition, Book II, 1903-1904; 1.3.7 (Box 3, Folder 7.0)
  - Swine, 1901-1910; 1.3.8 (Box 3, Folder 8.0)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture, Undated; 1.3.9 (Box 3, Folder 9.0)
- Grange and Farm Clubs, 1884-1915; 2; 0.50 Linear Feet
  The Grange and Farm Clubs series includes correspondence, booklets, clippings, and copies of constitutions and by-laws related to various grange and farm clubs to which Amoss belonged or with which he corresponded. Arrangement is alphabetical by topic.
  - Agricultural and Mechanical Society of Harford County, 1884; 2.1.1 (Box 1, Folder 1.0)
  - Farm Clubs, 1895-1915; 2.1.2 (Box 1, Folder 2.0)
  - Farmers Association of Harford County, [1896]; 2.1.3 (Box 1, Folder 3.0)
  - Farmers Club of Sandy Spring, Undated; 2.1.4 (Box 1, Folder 4.0)
  - Farmers Conventions, Harford County, Minutes Book, 1889; 2.1.5 (Box 1, Folder 5.0)
  - Farmers League of Maryland, 1910-1911; 2.1.6 (Box 1, Folder 6.0)
  - Montgomery County Farmers Bureau, Undated; 2.1.7 (Box 1, Folder 7.0)
  - Peninsula Produce Exchange of Maryland, 1908; 2.1.8 (Box 1, Folder 8.0)
- Correspondence, 1893-1926; 3; 3.00 Linear Feet
  The Correspondence series includes letters both to and from Amoss, largely dealing with arrangements for speakers and topics for Farmers' Institute lectures. Amoss corresponded with speakers on both a formal and informal basis. He continued to correspond with several speakers even after his tenure as director of Farmers' Institutes ended.
  This series also includes a handwritten letter from R. W. Silvester, President of MAC, regarding a meeting to discuss Amoss's election as director of Farmers' Institutes, as well as correspondence related to Amoss's dismissal from that position. Correspondence produced during Amoss's tenure at the U.S. Employment Agency deals with topics such as the farm labor shortage, World War I, and Negro labor. Folders labeled "Correspondence" contain miscellaneous letters to and from Amoss, including a few personal letters and some family correspondence.
  Arrangement is chronological where correspondents are various, and then alphabetical by correspondent or subject.
  - Correspondence, 1893-1900; 3.1.1 (Box 1, Folder 1.0)
  - Correspondence, 1901-1902; 3.1.2 (Box 1, Folder 2.0)
  - Correspondence, 1903; 3.1.3 (Box 1, Folder 3.0)
  - Correspondence, 1903-1905; 3.1.4 (Box 1, Folder 4.0)
  - Correspondence, 1906; 3.1.5 (Box 1, Folder 5.0)
  - Correspondence, 1907-1910; 3.1.6 (Box 1, Folder 6.0)
  - Correspondence, 1910-1916; 3.1.7 (Box 1, Folder 7.0)
  - Correspondence, 1917-1926; 3.1.8 (Box 1, Folder 8.0)
  - Correspondence -- Letter Press Volume, 1900-1910; 3.1.9 (Box 1, Folder 9.0)
  - Correspondence -- Letter Press Volume, 1900-1901; 3.2.1 (Box 2, Folder 1.0)
  - Correspondence -- Letter Press Volume, 1901-1903; 3.2.2 (Box 2, Folder 2.0)
  - Correspondence -- Letter Press Volume, 1901-1906; 3.2.3 (Box 2, Folder 3.0)
  - Correspondence -- Letter Press Volume, 1906-1910; 3.2.4 (Box 2, Folder 4.0)
  - Citizen's Bank of Laurel, 1902-1907; 3.3.1 (Box 3, Folder 1.0)
  - Close, C. P., 1909-1910; 3.3.2 (Box 3, Folder 2.0)
  - Coby [Cobey], W. W, 1905-1907; 3.3.3 (Box 3, Folder 3.0)
  - Corn Judging Contest, 1907-1908; 3.3.4 (Box 3, Folder 4.0)
  - Curryer, J. C., 1897-1905; 3.3.5 (Box 3, Folder 5.0)
  - Disagreement with Executive Board, 1910; 3.3.6 (Box 3, Folder 6.0)
  - Dismissal, 1910; 3.3.7 (Box 3, Folder 7.0)
  - Farmers League, Undated; 3.3.8 (Box 3, Folder 8.0)
  - Freight, 1906-1912; 3.3.9 (Box 3, Folder 9.0)
  - Gowell, G. M., 1906-1907; 3.3.10 (Box 3, Folder 10.0)
  - Green Ridge Orchard, 1913-1922; 3.3.11 (Box 3, Folder 11.0)
  - Gregg, O. C., 1896-1906; 3.3.12 (Box 3, Folder 12.0)
  - Hill, R. S., 1898-1910; 3.3.13 (Box 3, Folder 13.0)
  - Illinois Livestock Breeders Association, 1907; 3.3.14 (Box 3, Folder 14.0)
  - Jamestown Exposition, 1906; 3.3.15 (Box 3, Folder 15.0)
  - Johnson, W. G., 1897-1908; 3.3.16 (Box 3, Folder 16.0)
  - Kelsey, David, 1903-1909; 3.3.17 (Box 3, Folder 17.0)
  - Kent, Frank P., 1909-1910; 3.3.18 (Box 3, Folder 18.0)
  - Massey, W. F., 1901-1910; 3.3.19 (Box 3, Folder 19.0)
  - Massey, W. F., 1903-1908; 3.3.20 (Box 3, Folder 20.0)
  - McDonnell, H. B., 1910; 3.3.21 (Box 3, Folder 21.0)
  - Miller, H. P., 1901-1908; 3.3.22 (Box 3, Folder 22.0)
  - New England Education League [Scott, W.], 1911; 3.3.23 (Box 3, Folder 23.0)
  - Orr, T. E., 1902-1907; 3.3.24 (Box 3, Folder 24.0)
  - Patterson, H. J., 1899-1905; 3.3.25 (Box 3, Folder 25.0)
  - Patterson, H. J., 1906-1908; 3.3.26 (Box 3, Folder 26.0)
  - Patterson, H. J., 1909-1928; 3.4.1 (Box 4, Folder 1.0)
  - Pearson, R. A., 1899-1910; 3.4.2 (Box 4, Folder 2.0)
  - Powell, George T., 1896-1912; 3.4.3 (Box 4, Folder 3.0)
  - Powell, Harold, 1897-1907; 3.4.4 (Box 4, Folder 4.0)
  - Rankin, F. H., 1905-1909; 3.4.5 (Box 4, Folder 5.0)
  - Rice, James, 1897-1911; 3.4.6 (Box 4, Folder 6.0)
  - Robinson, James, 1897-1901; 3.4.7 (Box 4, Folder 7.0)
  - Sandles, A. P., 1908-1910; 3.4.8 (Box 4, Folder 8.0)
  - Silvester, R. W., 1896-1901; 3.4.9 (Box 4, Folder 9.0)
  - Silvester, R. W., 1902-1904; 3.4.10 (Box 4, Folder 10.0)
  - Silvester, R. W., 1905-1906; 3.4.11 (Box 4, Folder 11.0)
  - Silvester, R. W., 1907-1910; 3.4.12 (Box 4, Folder 12.0)
  - Smead, C. D., 1904-1910; 3.4.13 (Box 4, Folder 13.0)
  - Stabler, Augustus, 1906-1909; 3.4.14 (Box 4, Folder 14.0)
  - Stabler, Augustus -- Reports and Pamphlets, 1909; 3.4.15 (Box 4, Folder 15.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, January - March 1904; 3.5.1 (Box 5, Folder 1.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, April - June 1904; 3.5.2 (Box 5, Folder 2.0)
  - St. Louis World's Fair, July - December 1904; 3.5.3 (Box 5, Folder 3.0)
  - Symons, Thomas B., 1907-1910; 3.5.4 (Box 5, Folder 4.0)
  - Taliaferro, W. T. L., 1909; 3.5.5 (Box 5, Folder 5.0)
  - Thomas, H. C., 1909-1910; 3.5.6 (Box 5, Folder 6.0)
  - Todd, S. N., 1896-1908; 3.5.7 (Box 5, Folder 7.0)
  - True, A. C., 1899-1904; 3.5.8 (Box 5, Folder 8.0)
  - U. S. Employment Service, January - June 1918; 3.5.9 (Box 5, Folder 9.0)
  - U. S. Employment Service, July - December 1918; 3.5.10 (Box 5, Folder 10.0)
  - U. S. Employment Service, 1918; 3.5.11 (Box 5, Folder 11.0)
  - U. S. Employment Service, 1919-1921; 3.5.12 (Box 5, Folder 12.0)
  - Van Alstyne, Edward, 1898-1907; 3.6.1 (Box 6, Folder 1.0)
  - Van Alstyne, Edward, 1900-1910; 3.6.2 (Box 6, Folder 2.0)
  - Van Deman, H. E., 1901; 3.6.3 (Box 6, Folder 3.0)
  - Van Wagenen, Jared, 1905-1908; 3.6.4 (Box 6, Folder 4.0)
  - Watts, R. L., 1902-1910; 3.6.5 (Box 6, Folder 5.0)
  - Wing, Joseph, 1900-1909; 3.6.6 (Box 6, Folder 6.0)
- Clippings, 1897-1923 and undated; 4; 0.50 Linear Feet
  The Clippings series includes scrapbooks and loose clippings collected by Amoss. A significant portion of the clippings contained in the scrapbooks features items on the Farmers' Institutes, as well as articles of professional interest to Amoss on agricultural topics.
  This series includes clippings related to agricultural discoveries and improvements featured at the St. Louis World's Fair; corn breeding and the "Corn Special," a traveling farm education endeavor; development of farm lands in Maryland; marketing cut flowers; cost-of-living issues for farmers and the business of farming; and diseases of livestock.
  Loose clippings have been photocopied onto acid-free paper. Scrapbooks have been interleaved with acid-free paper. Arrangement of loose clippings is by topic. Arrangement of scrapbooks is chronological.
  - Corn, 1898-1908 and undated; 4.1.1 (Box 1, Folder 1.0)
  - Corn Special, 1904-1906; 4.1.2 (Box 1, Folder 2.0)
  - Cost of Living, 1910-1918 and undated; 4.1.3 (Box 1, Folder 3.0)
  - Cut Flowers, 1921; 4.1.4 (Box 1, Folder 4.0)
  - Education, 1897-1910 and undated; 4.1.5 (Box 1, Folder 5.0)
  - Farmers' Institutes, 1897, 1906; 4.1.6 (Box 1, Folder 6.0)
  - Livestock, 1908 and undated; 4.1.7 (Box 1, Folder 7.0)
  - Marketing, 1910-1912 and undated; 4.1.8 (Box 1, Folder 8.0)
  - Miscellaneous, 1890-1910 and undated; 4.1.9; Includes oversize (Box 1, Folder 9.0)
  - Oysters, 1906-1907; 4.1.10 (Box 1, Folder 10.0)
  - Scrapbook, 1897-1899, 1923; 4.1.11 (Box 1, Folder 11.0)
  - Scrapbook, 1887-1916; 4.1.12 (Box 1, Folder 12.0)
- Mt. Soma Farm, 1891-1929; 5; 0.50 Linear Feet
  The Mt. Soma Farm series includes items related to the running and maintenance of the Amoss family farm, known as Mt. Soma Farm, in Benson, Harford County, Maryland. Items include address books, advertisements and fliers, a poultry ledger, and horse records. An undated typescript for a biography of William L. Amoss is also part of this series. Arrangement is alphabetical by topic.
  - Address Books, Undated; 5.1.1 (Box 1, Folder 1.0)
  - Advertisements, 1910 and undated; 5.1.2 (Box 1, Folder 2.0)
  - Amoss Biography, Undated; 5.1.3 (Box 1, Folder 3.0)
  - Pamphlets and Fliers -- Agriculture, 1900-1917; 5.1.4 (Box 1, Folder 4.0)
  - Pamphlets and Fliers -- Labor, Undated; 5.1.5 (Box 1, Folder 5.0)
  - Soma Park Poultry Ledger, 1927-1929; 5.1.6 (Box 1, Folder 6.0)
  - Soma Farm Horse Records, 1891-1901; 5.1.7 (Box 1, Folder 7.0)
- Publications, 1886-1936; 6; 4.50 Linear Feet
  The Publications series includes pamphlets, books, journals, journal articles, and advertisements collected by William Amoss and his wife, Sarah Evelyn Breed. In addition to published reports and studies from domestic and international agricultural organizations, journals, journal articles, and a variety of farming and gardening manuals and pamphlets, this series includes a number of reports and articles collected by Amoss's wife during her tenure as Superintendent of the Southern Industrial Classes of Norfolk, Virginia, a branch of the Hampton Institute.
  Headings have been assigned to groups of titles in this series. A grouping of miscellaneous titles precedes these groupings, and then arrangement is alphabetical by heading, and then alphabetical by title. In cases where the heading is comprised of an organization's annual reports or several items bearing the same title, arrangement is chronological.
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- American League for Civic Improvement, October 1901; 6.1.1 (Box 1, Folder 1.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- Educational Manual Training: Advanced Knife Work; Elementary Knife Work; Paper Folding, 1903; 6.1.2 (Box 1, Folder 2.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- Farm Relief Speeches of Franklin W. Fort, 1926; 6.1.3 (Box 1, Folder 3.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- Finance and Banking Pamphlets, 1936 and undated; 6.1.4 (Box 1, Folder 4.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- How to Make Good Pictures, Undated; 6.1.5 (Box 1, Folder 5.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- International Congress on Tuberculosis, 1908; 6.1.6 (Box 1, Folder 6.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- Jefferson, the Seer: His Vision of a System of Public Education, 1903; 6.1.7 (Box 1, Folder 7.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- Mechanics' Arithmetic, 1889; 6.1.8 (Box 1, Folder 8.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- National Social Unit Organization, Bulletins, 1917-1918; 6.1.9 (Box 1, Folder 9.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- The Problem in the South: An Address before the Southern Educational Association, 1903; 6.1.10 (Box 1, Folder 10.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- The People: Issued in the Interest of Free, Universal and Equal Education., 1905; 6.1.11; Oversize (Box 1, Folder 11.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- The Rockefeller Foundation Review, 1928; 6.1.12 (Box 1, Folder 12.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- Supreme Court of District of Columbia Bill of Complaint [History of the Green Ridge Project], 1917; 6.1.13; Includes oversize (Box 1, Folder 13.0)
  - Miscellaneous Titles -- U. S. Employment Service [Annual Report of the Director General to the Secretary of Labor], 1918; 6.1.14 (Box 1, Folder 14.0)
  - African-American Education and Labor -- Atlanta University, 1898; 6.2.1 (Box 2, Folder 1.0)